

Svetoslav Mishev

Adress: Sofia, Bulgaria

Date of Birth: August, 1984

Email: svetlioo.m@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/svetoslavmishev

Developer profile: https://github.com/svetoslavmishev

Portfolio: https://svetoslavmishev.github.io

Phone: +359 883337815

SUMMARY

Hi there,

I am bright and ambitious person, who practicing and developing JavaScript applications. Strive to build beautiful and usable web Applications using best practices and standards. I specialize in front-end development, user experience using modern tools in the build process. I am familiar with most popular tools, libraries and frameworks like HTML+CSS, Bootstrap, MongoBD, Express, React, Angular2, etc. Followed the concept writing code every day and improving my expertise in web development every day. I did that more than 3 years, but in high intensity more than 1.5 years, as a student in Software University.

My goal is to work fully as a web developer with a progressive employer in a team of amazing people who share the same passion, and work daily to fulfil it.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

- Courteous, enthusiastic and creative person
- Responsible and flexible
- Quick learner and eager to further my skills
- Passion to learn new technologies and gaining knowledge in different science areas
- Full commitment, be a pleasant and friendly addition to the team
- Enjoy working in the industry and have a passion for creating new digital experiences

EDUCATION

CURRENTLY STUDING SOFTWARE ENGINEERING | APR 2017 - PRESENT

Software University, Sofia, Bulgaria

Major: Javascript Software Developer

POSTGRADUATE IN PROJECT MANAGEMENT | SEP 2013 - MAY 2015
University of Architecture, Civil Engineering and Geodesy, Sofia, Bulgaria

Master degree: INFRASTRUCTURE PROJECT MANAGEMENT

GRADUATE IN LAND SURVEYING ENGINEER | AUG 2003 - JUL 2009 University of Architecture, Civil Engineering and Geodesy, Sofia, Bulgaria

Master degree: **GEODESY AND GEOINFORMATICS**

Specialization: Satellite Geodesy based on Global Navigation Satellite Systems

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS

Front-End Technologies: HTML5, CCS3,

Bootstrap, JQuery

Frameworks and Libraries: ExpressJS,

NodeJS, ReactJS, Angular 2+

Programming Languages: JavaScript, C#,

Typescript

View engines: Handlebars, Pug

Databases: MongoDB/Mongoose

Version Control System: Git;

IDE: VS Code, WebStorm, Visual Studio **OS:** Microsoft Windows™, MS Office

products, MS Project

Basic Testing knowledge: Mocha, Chai

Tasks & Packages: Gulp, npm

CERTIFICATES OF KNOWLEDGE

- Javascript Basics
- JS Fundamentals
- JS Applications
- Express.js & Node.js
- ReactJS
- Angular 2+

EXPERIENCE

CHIEF SURVEY ENGINEER | MAR 2009 - PRESENT

Ministry of Defence, Sofia, Bulgaria

Collected land survey data using GPS/GNSS system;

Planned and conducted ground surveys designed to establish baselines, elevations, and other;

Responsible for the production of digital survey data using existing software packages;

Strong knowledge in Autodesk products as AutoCAD and Civil3D

SENIOR SURVEY ENGINEER | SEP 2009 - MAR 2017

Geodesy Cartography and Cadastre Agency, Sofia, Bulgaria

Cadastre, digital terrain models, terrain design, stakeout, controlling levels of projects, making longitudinal and transversal profiles.

Operated ArcGIS Information Systems and Spatial data

Creating national geodetic networks with high precision GPS/GNSS measurements

LAST PROJECTS AND COURSES

SpecialEvents, Angular6 Application - https://specialevents.herokuapp.com/

"SpecialEvents" is complex app, which helps users to perform a quick search about movies by title and get info for popularity, release date related website, etc.

Skills gained and practice with Angular:

- Consolidation of skills with Angular
- Based on Angular6 client-side and Progress Kinvey cloud-based database;
- Used additional programming concepts, specific to the Angular framework: models, interceptors, lazy loading, guards, users and administration roles, etc.;
- Integrating libraries Bootstrap v4, NgxPagination, NgxSpinner, NgxToaster notifications into the project;
- Create simple ExpressJS server to deploy in Heroku Cloud Application Platform

MovieFinder, Angular6 Application - https://movies-finder.herokuapp.com/

"MovieFinder" simple responsive app, which helps users to perform a quick search about movies by title and get info for popularity, release date related website, etc.

Skills gained and practice with Angular:

- Applying Typescript, custom Angular language;
- Based on MovieDB remote API;
- Used components, modules, observables, decorators, routing, request service as dependency injection(DI);
- Integrating and styling Bootstrapv4 alpha6 into the project;
- Wrote simple Express server to deploy in Heroku Cloud Application Platform

StadiumGuide, React.js Application - https://github.com/svetoslavmishev/ReactJS/tree/master/Stadium

This web application using React library and presents guide for detailed information about stadiums all over the world. Here my focus was not to design a good-looking page, but to develop most used features as user management, listing, create, edit and delete, etc.

Skills gained and practice with React.js:

- Using React's custom markup language, JSX, to clean up JavaScript code;
- Master the process of breaking down a complex component into many smaller pieces
- Full control with CRUD operations about users, stadiums, etc.;
- Integrating users and administrator roles;
- Wrote a RESTful API with Node.js and Expresss.js to store data in database as a JSON object;

ShopStop, Express.js & Node.js Application - https://github.com/svetoslavmishev/ExpressJS

"Shop Stop" is simple product catalog website, which consist of users, products and categories.

Skills gained and practice with Express.js & Node.js:

- Using MongoDB as database, Mongoose as a plugin to define database models and relations;
- Handling request/response with Express.js router;
- Integrated authentication with local strategy, JSON web token, storage session memory;
- Used dynamically Pug/Jade as view engine

EasyCashier, Single Page Application - https://easycashier.herokuapp.com

"EasyCashier" is SPA, which helps users (cashier) to handling multiple customers and cashiers, to compose their receipt, present list of all receipts, a receipt details view and reports about customers, product quantity and total price.

Skills gained and practice with SPA:

- Understanding and using jQuery library;
- Implement AJAX and REST service with Kinvey cloud-based backend;
- Dynamically html based on Handlebars as view engine
- Wrote simple Express server to deploy in Heroku Cloud Application Platform

ADDITIONAL PROGRAMING COURSES TAKEN

- ✓ Web Fundamentals HTML + CSS, *Telerik Academy*
- ✓ ES6 Javascript: The Complete Developer's Guide, Udemy
- ✓ Javascript for Front-End Development, SoftUni /Currently/

LANGUAGES

Bulgarian – Native English – Work level